<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on My blog</title>
    <link>https://novores.github.io/en/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on My blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>id</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 07:02:58 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novores.github.io/en/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Share Files Between Devices with Wormhole William</title>
      <link>https://novores.github.io/en/post/wormhole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 07:02:58 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.github.io/en/post/wormhole/</guid>
      
        <description>wormhole-william is the go language implementation of magic-wormhole</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Activate Bluetooth With Just A Terminal on Linux</title>
      <link>https://novores.github.io/en/post/bluetoothctl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 23:01:42 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.github.io/en/post/bluetoothctl/</guid>
      
        <description>Intro bluetooth is one of the technologies that must exist in every computer device, because of its many, many uses, not only for file transfers, but bluetooth can also be used to connect sound wirelessly.
according to wikipedia
Bluetooth is the industry specification for wireless personal area networks (PAN). bluetooth connects and can be used to exchange information between devices. The specifications of this bluetooth device are developed and distributed by the bluetooth special interest group.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Ignore Certain Packages To Upgrade in Archlinux</title>
      <link>https://novores.github.io/en/post/mengabaikan-package-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 07:02:58 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.github.io/en/post/mengabaikan-package-archlinux/</guid>
      
        <description>Background sometimes when we want to update a package, there are things we want to ignore to update. for example, if there is a lack of quota I will make one large package to be ignored, one of which is libreoffice, this package one of the big packages and not too important to upgrade in my opinion, that I have
Attention be careful when choosing packages to ignore for upgrading make sure there are no dependencies to depend on Mainly the Linux kernel</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emptty: A Very Simple Display Manager</title>
      <link>https://novores.github.io/en/post/cara-mudah-mengkonfigurasi-emptty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.github.io/en/post/cara-mudah-mengkonfigurasi-emptty/</guid>
      
        <description>description emptty itself is cli based, this is what makes it quite simple to operate, emptty is a simple display manager, emptty is written in the go language. but there are some configurations that we must determine first, so that emptty can work as we want.
Installing unfortunately emptty is only available in the aur and void repos. but calm down you can install emptty via cloning.
type the following command</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>