<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Novores</title>
    <link>https://novores.xyz/en/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Novores</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 06:31:13 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novores.xyz/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Added Cactus Comments to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://novores.xyz/en/post/cactus-comment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 06:31:13 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.xyz/en/post/cactus-comment/</guid>
      <description>Introduction hugo is a feature-rich static site generator. one of them is the comment feature, to add this comment feature we only need to add a shortcode to the frontmatter of our blog. but unfortunately this feature is only available for disqus. I personally don&amp;rsquo;t really like disquss because of its proprietary.
if we want to add comments from other providers, then we have to write the shortcode itself.
I prefer cactus comment where comments that enter the blog/website will be directly linked through the matrix account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Share Files Between Devices with Wormhole William</title>
      <link>https://novores.xyz/en/post/wormhole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 07:02:58 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.xyz/en/post/wormhole/</guid>
      <description>Description wormhole-william is the go language implementation of magic-wormhole.
Wormhole itself is a command-line tool that contains commands to send and receive files, directories, and text, securely. this is to send and receive files using easy-to-read wormhole code as the “unlocking key” example of the unlocking key in question:5-boy-farming.
The wormhole also provides end-to-end encryption, the endpoint is connected to the same 2 endpoints.
 why use wormhole-william instead of wormhole?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Activate Bluetooth With Just A Terminal on Linux</title>
      <link>https://novores.xyz/en/post/bluetoothctl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 23:01:42 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.xyz/en/post/bluetoothctl/</guid>
      <description>Intro bluetooth is one of the technologies that must exist in every computer device, because of its many, many uses, not only for file transfers, but bluetooth can also be used to connect sound wirelessly.
according to wikipedia
 Bluetooth is the industry specification for wireless personal area networks (PAN). bluetooth connects and can be used to exchange information between devices. The specifications of this bluetooth device are developed and distributed by the bluetooth special interest group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Ignore Certain Packages To Upgrade in Archlinux</title>
      <link>https://novores.xyz/en/post/mengabaikan-package-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 07:02:58 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.xyz/en/post/mengabaikan-package-archlinux/</guid>
      <description>Background sometimes when we want to update a package, there are things we want to ignore to update. for example, if there is a lack of quota I will make one large package to be ignored, one of which is libreoffice, this package one of the big packages and not too important to upgrade in my opinion, that I have
 Attention be careful when choosing packages to ignore for upgrading make sure there are no dependencies to depend on Mainly the Linux kernel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticate Git With SSH</title>
      <link>https://novores.xyz/en/post/connect-ke-github-dengan-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.xyz/en/post/connect-ke-github-dengan-ssh/</guid>
      <description>Intro authenticating git with ssh is by generating a pair of encryption keys asymmetrically, where the key is stored on the system and the other is stored on the server.
in other words the computer will not get access rights if the key that is paired is wrong or different, so this allows a very, very secure connection than we use https.
and another advantage that we no longer use tokens when setting up the repository but just the password we set if you set it later when generating or generating ssh keys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emptty: A Very Simple Display Manager</title>
      <link>https://novores.xyz/en/post/cara-mudah-mengkonfigurasi-emptty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.xyz/en/post/cara-mudah-mengkonfigurasi-emptty/</guid>
      <description>description emptty itself is cli based, this is what makes it quite simple to operate, emptty is a simple display manager, emptty is written in the go language. but there are some configurations that we must determine first, so that emptty can work as we want.
Installing unfortunately emptty is only available in the aur and void repos. but calm down you can install emptty via cloning.
type the following command</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Touchpad Configuration in Linux</title>
      <link>https://novores.xyz/en/post/cara-mengaktifkan-tap-to-click-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novores.xyz/en/post/cara-mengaktifkan-tap-to-click-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Intro when using linux we sometimes don&amp;rsquo;t find the computer working system properly, we are required to be do it yourself.
therefore we must really understand how computers actually work, and are required to independently solve existing problems. One of the first problems that I felt when I first tried Linux was the problem of not working tap on the laptop touchpad, I will try to solve this problem in detail so that it is easy for you to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
